行  波拉  真是太好了
Yeah, Paula, that sounds perfect.
好  就这样说定了
Yeah, close the deal.
谢谢你  你也是
Thank you. And to you.
想知道我为什么在这儿吗
Ask me why I'm here?
我每天都问自己这个问题
You know, I ask myself that question every day.
我的经纪人波拉带来个好消息
That was Paula, my agent, with big news
是关于《希特热浪》的
about my book "Heat Wave."
-猜猜是什么消息  -猜就表示我在乎
- Wanna guess?  -Guessing would imply caring.
我给你点提示
I'll give you a hint.
报纸上的头条可能会是
The headlines in the trades might read,
卡塞尔的畅销书将点燃大银幕
"Castle best seller to 'heat' up big screen."
你的书要被拍成电影啦
Your book is being made into a movie?
而你的银幕形象将永远被人铭记
And you are about to be immortalized on the silver screen.
事实上  妮基·希特才是被铭记的人
Actually, Nikki Heat is going to be immortalized,
-不是我  -没错  可以这样说
- not me.  - Yes, well, technically,
但大家都知道她是以你为原型的
but it's been widely publicized that you are the inspiration.
你想让谁在电影中扮演你呢
So who would you like to play you in the movie?
哇  你不是开玩笑吧
Whoa. Are you kidding?
真的要拍一部妮基·希特的电影吗
They're really making a Nikki Heat movie?
兄弟  是我的祈祷应验了吗
Dude, did I call it or what?
恭喜你  老兄
Ah, congrats, bro.
-谢谢  -这样如何
- Thank you!  -What do you think,
能找詹姆斯·麦卡沃伊
can we get James McAvoy
来扮演我这个"莱利警探"吗
for Detective Raley?
那我选贾维尔·巴尔登[曾主演《午夜巴塞罗那》]
I'm gonna go with Javier Bardem.
-我是贝克特  -我想报告一起谋杀案
- Beckett. - Yeah, I'd like to report a murder.
有地址吗
Do you have an address?
告诉你就没意思了
Where's the fun in that?
好吧
Okay.
你是谁
Who is this?
你的粉丝
Oh, a fan.
-再告诉我一些线索  -追踪信号
- Tell me more about this murder.  - Tracing.
好吧  是我干的
Well, I did it.
你只需知道这点就够了
And that's all you need to know.
找到了
Got it.
-喂  -42大道和莱辛顿大道交汇处
- Hello?  - 42nd and Lex.
-那里是中央车站  -出发
- That's Grand Central Station.  - Yeah, let's go.
根据追踪显示
According to tech,
电话是在倒数第二个电话亭打的
the phone call came from the second booth on the end.
这是他的钱包
Here's his wallet.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You got it.
他叫亚历克斯·彼得曼  住在多布斯费里
His name's Alex Peterman, lives in Dobbs Ferry.
这不是劫杀
So it wasn't a robbery.
他是人身伤害诉讼律师
He's a personal injury attorney.
准备搭晚班列车回家
Taking the late train home.
除了枪伤外有没有别的发现
Anything other than GSWs?
没有  只发现胸口被点45口径手枪射中五枪
Nope, just the 5 shots to the chest from a .45.
点45口径手枪动静儿很大啊
A .45 makes a pretty loud snap, crackle and pop.
大堂里不可能
I find it hard to believe no one heard it
没人听见
on the main concourse.
他肯定用了消音器
He must have used a suppressor
等火车经过时才开的枪
and waited for the train to pass by.
必须承认这个事实  纽约人可是
And let's face it-- New Yorkers are famous
非礼勿听勿视的"模范"
for their "Hear no evil, See no evil" attitude.
验尸后一有结果
I'll give you a call with an update
-我就给你电话  -谢谢
- once I get him back to the lab.  - Thank you.
快问快答  妮基·希特电影中要谁来演你
Quick--who do you want to play you in the Nikki Heat movie?
哈莉·贝瑞[性感黑人奥斯卡影后]
Halle Berry.
看到没  人家回答得多好啊
See? Some people are just great at that game.
我们可以安排谁来演你呢
You know who we could get for you?
安吉丽娜  不行
Angelina. No.
凯特·贝克特  就凯特·贝金赛尔吧
Kate Beckett, Kate Beckinsale.
我们可以叫你凯贝姐
We'll call you K-Becks.
伙计们  有什么进展吗
Hey, guys, where are we on the case?
有个女人说她在8点45分左右
We got a woman who says that she heard
听到一声巨响
a loud sound around 8:45--
听起来像是车门猛地一关
Sounded like a car door slamming.
她还说看到一个大概三十多岁
And she said she saw a white male,
中等个头的白人男性离开候车室
30s, average height, exiting the waiting room,
从通往42大道的出口处迅速离开
moving very quickly to the 42nd exit.
他身穿黑色外套  戴着黑色棒球帽
Said he was wearing a black coat, black ball cap,
和太阳镜
sunglasses
而且还有些胡须  可能是山羊胡
and had some sort of beard, maybe a goatee.
看看有没有其他目击者
All right, let's see if anyone
也做出相同描述
can corroborate her description,
然后完成人像图
and let's make up a sketch,
给亚历克斯·彼得曼的家人辨认
show it to Alex Peterman's family,
看他们是否认识凶手
see if they recognize the killer.
怎么了
What is it?
他打电话来举报自己的罪行
He called to report his crime.
他的声音
And that voice...
听起来就像以此取乐
It's like he did this for fun.
你起的真早
Hey. You're up early.
是啊  我要去验尸房和贝克特见面
Yes, I have a date with Beckett at the morgue.
你们俩串通什么阴谋诡计呢
What nefarious plots are you two hatching?
我的生日就快到了
My birthday is coming up.
我觉得你该告诉他  奶奶
I think you should tell him, gram.
有时候他的建议还是挺不错的
Sometimes he gives good advice.
-有时候  -是的  可能你说的对
- Sometimes?  - Yeah, maybe you're right.
但我可不想听你的冷嘲热讽
But I am not in the mood for any of your cavalier quips.
我会如临大敌般认真对待
I'll be serious as a shark attack.
切特让我搬过去同居
Chet has asked me to move in with him.
我跟奶奶说了  这太快了点
I told her... that I thought it was too soon.
他们才约会了几个月而已
They've only been dating a few months.
我这个年纪  一寸光阴一寸金
When you get to be our age, every minute counts.
为此  我列出了优劣势对比
To that end, I have made a list of pros and cons.
目前优势占上风
So far the pros are winning.
优势  他让我觉得年轻
"Pro--he makes me feel young."
-我也让你觉得年轻啊  -亲爱的
- I make you feel young.  - Oh, darling.
劣势  我不想住在别的男人家里
"Cons--I don't want to live in another man's home."
你不是别人  而且我已把你调教好了
You are not another man. Besides, I trained you.
谁知道切特这些年来
Who knows what bad habits Chet picked up
沾染了些什么坏习惯啊
along the way, you know?
妈  无论你怎样决定  我都支持你
Mother, whatever you decide, I will support you,
就和上次  你同居的那个男人卷走了你的
The same way I have since the last man you lived with
所有家产时一样
stole your life savings.
死因是遭受多处枪伤
Cause of death is multiple gunshot wounds.
毒化检验显示  大概在死前一小时
Tox indicates he had a martini about an hour
他喝了一杯马提尼
before he died.
除此之外
Other than that,
尸体就没什么特别的了
there is nothing interesting about the body.
那你为什么打电话给我
So then why the call?
尸体没什么特别  麻烦让一下
The body isn't interesting. Excuse me.
但弹壳很奇特
But the bullets are.
看一下子弹底部的记号
Check out the marking on the end of the slugs.
是配件工厂加的标记吗
Aftermarket factory stamps?
不是
No.
这些不是标记而是字母
Those aren't stamps. They're letters.
看  手工雕刻的
And look, they're hand-etched.
它们可以组成一个词
They spell something.
那个词是
They spell...
金妮
"Kinki."
不是
No.
是"妮基"
"Nikki."
妮基·希特
Nikki Heat.
所以他才给我打电话
That's why he called me.
还说是我的粉丝
That's why he said he was a fan.
谋杀是疯狂的献礼
He dedicated this murder to me.
他知道妮基只是个虚构的人物吗
Does he realize she's a fictional character not a real person?
显然他有妄想症  但考虑到妮基·希特
Obviously, he's delusional, but given that Nikki Heat
是以贝克特探长为原型
is based on Detective Beckett,
他可能把这两者搞混淆了
maybe he's confusing the two.
我们给亚历克斯·彼得曼的家人看了
And we showed Alex Peterman's family
嫌疑人的画像  他们不认识他
the sketch of our suspect. He did not look familiar.
在取证上有什么进展
How are we on forensics?
鉴证组已经采集了大约两百个指纹
C.S.U. grabbed about 200 fingerprints,
上千种纤维和60多份DNA样本
a thousand fibers and 60 odd D.N.A. samples,
这还只是在电话亭采集的
And that was just from the phone box.
他们会在处理完积压的工作后
They're working them up now...
着手进行化验
after they clear their backlog.
贝克特  有人打电话找希特警探
Beckett. Guy on the phone's asking for Detective Heat.
妮基  你收到我的第一条信息了吗
Nikki, did you get the first part of my message?
是的  收到了
Yes, I did.
第二条在中央公园的旋转木马那里
Well, the second is at the Central Park carousel.
她被点45口径手枪射中4枪
She was shot 4 times with a .45.
死者身体左侧的挫伤
There are contusions on the victim's left side
和点45口径枪口形状吻合
consistent with the muzzle of a .45
是枪口卡在肋骨间所致
being jammed into her ribs.
我猜凶手是左撇子
I'm guessing the killer is left-handed.
子弹是鉴证组从马车背面拔出来的吗
C.S.U. pull the slugs from the back of the carriage?
是的  子弹上有字母
Yes, there were letters on the slugs.
写的是"将"
They spell "W-I-L-L."
所以他是在传达信息
So he's sending a message.
妮基将...
"Nikki will"...
什么呢  妮基将怎么样
What? Nikki will what?
谢谢  蕾妮
Thank you, Lanie.
这家伙是个职业级的连环杀手
I guess it's official. Our guy is a serial killer.
一个连环杀手
I would think that a serial killer
对于犯罪小说家来说
would be like the holy grail
-就像圣杯一样可贵  -可能是吧
- for a crime novelist.  - I guess it would be
如果不是和妮基·希特有关就好了
or if it weren't for the Nikki Heat at all.
我觉得我该负部分责任
I'm feeling a little bit responsible.
是吗  那么因为《匆匆太匆匆》这首歌
Really? Like the Beatles are responsible
披头士乐队就该为杀人狂查理·曼森负责吗
for Charles Manson 'cause of "Helter skelter"?
还是说  朱迪·福斯特要为
Or is it more like Jodie Foster is responsible
约翰·欣克利刺杀里根总统而负责
for John Hinckley shooting Reagan?
如果我没有塑造妮基·希特这个角色
If I hadn't created Nikki Heat--
他还是会杀人
He would still be killing.
只是他会找别的理由
He'd just find another reason why.
好了  各位  请让一下
All right, folks. Make way.
出什么事了
Now what's going on?
如果不是刚刚有飞碟在公园那头降落
Either a U.F.O. just landed on the other side of the park...
就是联邦调查局来插手这件案子了
Or else the FBI is here to claim jurisdiction over this case.
可能他们只是想在队伍还没排成长龙前
Maybe they just want to ride on the carousel
骑下旋转木马
before the line gets too long.
以旋转木马为中心围成方圆三米的警戒区
Rope off a 10-foot circumference around the carousel.
采集指纹  查找证据
Sweep for prints and trace evidence.
关闭公园的六号入口
Close off the park entrance at 6th.
检查所有人行道
Work up the entire footpath.
开始了
Here goes.
我猜你就是妮基·希特吧
Nikki Heat I presume.
我是贝克特  凯特·贝克特探长
It's Beckett. Detective Kate Beckett.
我看过《时尚》杂志中你的报道  久仰了
Yeah, I read all about you in "Cosmo."
那你肯定就是著名的作家以及跟班
And you must be the celebrity writer tagalong,
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle.
-我是特工乔丹·肖  -乔丹·肖
- Special agent Jordan Shaw.  - Jor-Jordan Shaw?
是1991年侦破
The same Jordan Shaw that broke
哈得逊河谷杀人案的那个乔丹·肖吗
the Hudson Valley strangler case back in 1991?
我的拼字游戏也玩的不错[也有擅长摸索之意]
I also play a mean game of scrabble.
既然我们互相都认识了  我想看看尸体
Now that we all know each other, I'd like to see the body.
特工肖  我的手下已经封锁了这片区域
Agent Shaw, my people have already secured the area.
鉴定组在现场取证
C.S.U. is on the scene,
警员也在公园内收集证词
and we are canvassing the park.
我很高兴看到这些装甲兵
So as happy as I am to see the cavalry,
但这里实在不需要你们
there's really not much left here for you to do.
探长  是上面的头儿
Detective, the Gods in the marble halls
派我来缉拿凶手的  不管有没有你的帮助
have sent me here to catch a killer, which I will do
这都是我要完成的任务  懂了吗
with or without your help, okay?
现在我能看尸体了吗
Now could I see the body?
这真应该拍进电影里
That is so going in the movie.
你能再说一遍吗
Can you say that again,
从"上面的头儿"那里开始
but start from "marble halls"?
警员在垃圾桶里找到了这个钱包
Unis pulled this from a trash bin. Wallet's inside.
死者名叫米歇尔·刘易斯
The vic's name is Michelle Lewis.
从名片来看  她是个职业遛狗人
According to her business card, she's a dog walker.
这里有个指纹
There's a print here,
但比死者的指纹大
And it's too large to be our victim's.
拿去化验室吧
Let's get it to the lab for--
你在做什么
What are you doing?
指纹已经传到化验室进行检测了
That print is already in the lab and being processed.
操作简单  轻巧易携带
No muss, no fuss, no black powder on your clothes.
居然有如此神奇的装备
Wow. There's an app for that?
这是我加入联调局的动力
That's why I joined the FBI,
卡塞尔先生  装备一流
Mr. Castle, for the toys.
我迫不及待想看看尸体了
I'm really eager to see that body.
我能看看那...
Can I take a look at that--
以后有机会再看吧
Be a chance to check it later.
怎么回事
What is going on?
他们在搭建作战室
They're setting up the war room.
作战室
War room?
把你知道的乔丹·肖的一切都告诉我
Tell me everything you know about Jordan Shaw.
她就像是联调局版本的你
She is like the Federal you.
她很出色  相当的出色
She is good. She is real good.
她在二十五岁那年侦破了
She cracked open that Hudson Valley strangler case
哈得逊河谷杀人案
when she was just 25.
我听说他们凭一张超速罚单逮住了他
I thought they caught him off of a speeding ticket.
别问我他怎么被逮住的
Well, don't ask me how,
但她分析出凶手开的是越野车
but she profiled that he drove a Yugo.
他被捕时  车后座绑着一个女孩
They found a girl tied up in the back.
乔丹·肖救了那女孩的命
Uh-huh. Jordan Shaw saved that girl's life.
以前也没见你看见谁这么兴奋
I've never seen you so excited to meet anyone before.
没有  我只是  我很佩服...
No, I just--I'm-- Oh, I'm impressed with--
借过  当心
Excuse us. Watch it.
我们现在能去作战室看看吗
Can we go see the war room now?
你也在搜索匹配指纹吗
You're running partials, too, right?
正在检索整个数据库
Through all databases.
化验室会以最快速度反馈我们跟进的资料
The lab's getting us information as fast as we can follow up.
不是说鉴证组积压的活儿堆积如山吗
I thought there was a backlog at the lab.
我有联邦加急令  所以可以优先
I have a federal fast pass, so I get to jump the line.
目前  我们从两个案发现场得到的
Currently we are running 35 solid leads
DNA  指纹
based on DNA., prints,
及蛛丝马迹中  掌握了35条可靠的线索
trace evidence found from both crime scenes,
联调局的二维码处理软件正分析这些线索
and we're running it through the FBI data matrix.
以此来找出受害人之间的联系
The matrix also looks for a connection between the victims
以防凶手在固定区域以固定手法
in case the killer has a type or a favorite hunting ground
有计划性地行凶
or isn't killing randomly.
亚历克斯·彼得曼  米歇尔·刘易斯
Both Alex Peterman and Michelle Lewis belonged to
同是威克斯健身房的会员  但区域不同
the same Wessex gym, but they went to different locations.
他们都是现代艺术博物馆的会员
They were both members of MoMA.
他们的狗是在同一家动物防虐协会领养的
Hmm. They both adopted their dogs from the same ASPCA.
听起来它为你做了本该你做的活儿
Sounds like it does your job for you.
机器能收集信息  但它不能思考
A machine can collate. It can't think.
得用心去理解罪犯的心理
It takes a mind to hunt a mind.
分析下这家伙吧
Take this guy.
他主动报警  检举自己的犯罪行为
He calls the police to report his own crime,
喜欢在人口密集的地区杀人
likes to kill in heavily populated areas
然后用弹壳传递信息
and uses bullets as messages.
这种嚣张的怪胎  通常是智力有问题
Now most of these stalker types can barely tie their own shoes.
但他与众不同  相当聪明
This one's different, smarter.
听你的语气似乎是欣赏他
You almost sound like you admire him.
我对他的欣赏
I admire him the way
如同电影《大白鲨》中罗伯特·肖对鲨鱼的欣赏一样
Robert Shaw admired the shark in "Jaws."
我越了解他
The better I know him,
就越容易逮住他
the easier it'll be to catch him.
就像我写作的时候一样
That's like when I'm writing.
凶手的声音是伪造的
The killer's voice doesn't sound authentic
但我并不知道他的动机
unless I understand his motivation.
这家伙想引人注目
Well, this guy likes to make a scene.
就算他是纵火犯  我也不吃惊
I wouldn't be surprised if he was also an arsonist.
我想妮基·希特这个角色
In fact, I think that's what drew him
最初吸引他的是
to the Nikki Heat character in the first place --
"热浪"这个名字
her name.
说到"热浪"探长
Speaking of Detective Heat...
大伙  听着
Whoa. Whoa. Guys. Listen.
不是我不喜欢版税  但
Not that I don't appreciate the royalties, but, uh,
你们要一百本《希特热浪》做什么
why do you need a hundred copies of "Heat Wave"?
如果凶手为妮基·希特着迷
If our killer is obsessed with Nikki Heat,
我们也得这么做
then so are we.
艾弗里  请念概要
Avery, cliff notes, please.
一个地产大亨遇害
A real estate tycoon is killed.
妮基·希特警探负责此案
Detective Nikki Heat catches the case
并根据杀人动机调查嫌疑人
and investigates suspects who wanted the man dead.
其中当然包括他的娇妻
There's a trophy wife, of course,
还有危险的犯罪团伙
dangerous mobsters---
对不起  打断一下
Uh, uh, excuse me.
这本可是《纽约时报》榜上的畅销书啊
It's--It's a--It's a "New York times" best-seller.
没必要像念经一样
I don't think there's a need
读的干巴巴的
to make it sound quite so dry.
谢了
Thanks.
希特的生活
Heat's life is complicated by
因记者詹姆森·洛克而复杂起来
a reporter named Jameson Rook,
他为了写作整天跟着她转
who's following her around for an article he's writing.
希特和洛克常常斗嘴
Heat and Rook verbally spar,
在第十一章
and in chapter 11,
终于承认彼此吸引  然后做爱
admit their attraction for one another and have sex.
这是小说
It's fiction.
最后真相大白
In the end, when the killer's revealed,
凶手其实就是
it turns out it's actually--
等等  别剧透哦
Oh, oh, oh. Spoiler alert.
鉴于卡塞尔先生有着艺术家的敏感性
In deference to Mr. Castle's artistic sensitivity,
大家还是在书中找出凶手的身份吧
you can all read the book to find out the identity of the killer.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你们想要签名的话
And if you want me to autograph those for you,
可以在这排个队
just form a single file line right here.
也可以不排
Or not.
有消息了
We got a hit.
第二位死者钱包上小指的指纹
That pinkie print off the second victim's purse
属于名叫唐纳德·索尔特的人  曾两次入狱
belongs to a Donald Salt, 2-time loser,
2005年过失杀人罪  现在是假释期
on parole for a manslaughter conviction in 2005.
和你们从中央车站采集的
They just matched it to the partial pinkie print
部分小指指纹也吻合
your team recovered from grand central.
两个小指指纹
Two pinkie prints?
那么说他去过车站和旋转木马
So he was at the station and the carousel.
钱包把他和死者联系了起来
And the purse puts him with our victim.
行动吧
Let's mount up.
好的  刚停车
Yeah. Okay. Just pulling up now.
是的  明白
Yep, got it.
索尔特住在那栋砖房里
Salt lives in that brick building.
他的假释监管说他一小时前下班了
His supervisor says he left work an hour ago.
他现在应该在家
So he should be home by now.
等增援一来  立马逮捕他
When the others get here, we'll take him.
他在做什么
What is he doing?
他啊  满足自己的好奇心呗
He, um, touches things.
夜视镜
Night vision goggles.
我想我的那个型号更先进些
I think I have the newer model though.
也许《希特热浪》第三部里
You know, maybe in my third book,
妮基·希特会和联调局的
Nikki Heat will cross swords
冷美人分析专家正面交锋
with a good-looking, yet coldhearted FBI profiler.
书名是《希特在联调局》
Call it "Federal Heat."
当我没说
Or maybe not.
你们俩的性关系维持多久了
So how long have you two been sleeping together?
我  我们没有性关系
I'm... We're-- We're not sleeping together.
他只是在观察我
We--He-- He just observes me.
我看出他用什么眼神观察了
Yeah. I've seen how he observes you.
她说的是事实  撇开我的第二任妻子不谈
No, she's right. Aside from my second wife,
这是我经历过的
this is the most sexless relationship
最无性的关系
I've ever been in.
对于人  我观察分析有些日子了
I've been profiling people for a long time.
我很少看错的
I'm hardly ever wrong.
这次你错了
Well, this time you are... wrong.
如果你们没有性关系
So if you're not sleeping together,
你为什么让他围着你转
why do you keep him around?
别当我是聋子
You know I can hear you?
事实上  他出人意料的有用
He's actually proven to be surprisingly helpful.
我也只能相信你了
Hmm. Have to take your word on that.
把电击枪放下
Put the taser down.
小组到了
Okay, the team's here.
你待在车里
You stay in the car.
卡塞尔  她说了  待在车里
You heard her, Castle. Stay.
至少帮我打开窗户吧
Could you at least crack the window for me?
跟上  我们走  快点
Come on. Let's go. Move, move.
速战速决  避免伤亡
Let's make it quick and bloodless.
上  上  上
Go, go, go.
等等
Hang on.
站住  联邦调查局
Stop! FBI! Hey!
看吧  我帮上忙了
See, I'm helping.
乖  待会儿给你买个冰淇淋
Yeah. I'll buy you an ice cream later.
特工肖  情况不妙
Agent Shaw, we got a problem.
他的小指断了
His pinkie finger's missing.
谁是妮基·希特
Which one of you is Nikki Heat?
那天我上交易网站
So I was on one of those internet barter sites,
想找
and I was looking--
我想找什么并不重要
It, uh, doesn't matter what I was looking for.
重要的是我看见一则广告
But I came across the ad.
高价收购手指
"Finger wanted. Will pay top dollar."
一个小指出价多少
And what's top dollar for a pinkie finger?
五千美元
5,000 bucks.
听起来跟真的似的
Sounds like a real deal.
卖个肾也没那么多钱
Hey, you get less than that for a kidney.
所以我给他回了邮件
So anyway, I e-mailed him back.
告诉他  他想要的我都能给
I told him I had everything he wanted.
然后你就把手指给他了
You gave him the finger.
他还有什么要求
What more did he want?
他要求我有暴力犯罪的案底
He wanted me to have a violent felony conviction
并且最近刚刚获得假释
and to be recently paroled.
还要求我心甘情愿地经受一次
And you also had to be willing to suffer through
不体面的错误逮捕
the indignity of a false arrest.
他告诉我妮基·希特警探会来抓我
He told me Detective Nikki Heat would be coming for me.
可能还会有身体接触
And it might get physical.
但他没提到"美国上尉"[漫画书中的英雄人物]
He didn't mention anything about Captain America
和他的电击枪
with the taser gun.
他警告过你
So he warned you
他会把你的指纹印在凶案现场
that he would be planting your print at a murder scene.
所以你才会有不在场证据
Which is why you have an alibi.
我每晚都坐在麦克索利酒吧
I was perched on my favorite bar stool
我最喜欢的座位上  直到打烊
at Mcsorley's until closing every night
从那个人把我的手指装进
since that man took my digit
冷却器带走的那晚开始
and walked away with it in his cooler.
是这个男人吗
Is this the man?
不能肯定  我没见到他的真面目
I'm not sure. I didn't really see him.
他带着帽子和太阳镜
He had a hat and sunglasses.
你的手指是谁包扎的
Who bandaged your finger?
是他
He did.
他还说你会注意到的
He said you'd notice.
温柔点  妮基
Ooh, be gentle with me, Nikki.
这里有数字
There's numbers here.
看起来像组密码
This looks like a code.
断指
Severed digits,
和密码  很像我书里的内容
a secret code--This is like one of my books.
你真应该和我一起侦查那起易头案
You should've been with me on the recapitator case.
是凤凰城那起凶手调换死者头部的案子吗
What, that guy in Phoenix who switched his victims' heads?
那居然是你负责的案子
That was your case?
技术人员把这些数字
Our techs have run the numbers
进行了所有的常规密码分析
through all conventional cryptology.
还是破解不了
We can't crack it.
什么意思
Which means what?
要么我们不了解编码规则
There's either a reference key that we don't have
要么这就是一排随机数字
or the code itself is just a random string of numbers.
这绝对不是随机的
It's not random.
他买下一个人的手指
He bought another man's finger
留下指纹
so he could leave a print
给线索让我们找到这组数字
that would lead us directly to this code.
这是他嘲弄妮基的手段
It's how he taunts Nikki.
就像在说  以你的智商能揭开谜底吗
"Are you clever enough to solve my riddle?"
所以不管编码规则是什么
So whatever this reference key is,
他都认为你能发现
he thinks you can find it.
这些数字能代表无数种含义
Those numbers could mean anything.
左边一栏都小于300
Well, the left-hand column is less than 300.
右边一栏不超过260
Right-hand column is no more than 260.
成对组合很可能组合成一个字
And the combination of the joined pair most likely yields a word.
就是字
Words.
应该是《希特热浪》
It's "Heat wave."
通常的排版
When we typeset a manuscript,
是一页300个字
it's usually 300 words a page.
但《希特热浪》不到三百页
And "Heat wave" is less than 300 pages.
第一栏是页码
First column is a page number...
79页  第二栏是单词
79. Second column is a word.
32  第33个字是  我
32, 33. "I."
126页第80个字是  将
126--80, "Will."
145页第204个字是  杀
145--204, "Kill."
我要杀
"I will kill"...
等等  我在上传文档
Hang on. I'm uploading the text right now.
我将在
I will kill
今晚午夜之前杀人
someone else before
除非你阻止我
midnight tonight unless you stop me."
午夜  还剩8小时
Midnight. That's eight hours away.
他给我们时限  挑战我们去阻止他
He's putting us on the clock. He's daring us to stop him.
还是用老方法吗
Kickin' it old-school?
白板对我来说总是有用
The white board's always worked for me.
我已经仔细检查过地铁路线
I've been going over subway routes,
希望能找出规律
trying to see if I can trace a pattern
从中央车站到旋转木马
from Grand Central to the Carousel
再到下一站  可到现在还毫无头绪
to the next location, and so far, nothing definitive.
也许他选择受害人
Well, maybe there's something
是遵循着什么规律的
about how he chooses his victims.
首先男性  然后女性
First a man, then a woman.
律师和遛狗人
A lawyer and a dog walker?
面对现实吧  根本没有规律
Let's face it. There's no pattern there.
不可能预测到他的下一个目标
There's no way to predict where he's gonna go next,
现在已经九点了  我们没时间了
and it's already 9:00, and we're out of time.
每一次谋杀  他都归因于妮基·希特
And every murder he commits in the name of Nikki Heat...
一位睿智的女性曾经告诉过我
A very wise woman once told me,
约翰·欣克利刺杀里根总统
you can't blame Jodie Foster
不能归罪于朱迪·福斯特
for John Hinckley.
但你可以因为影片《尼姆岛》责难她
But you can blame her for "Nim's Island."
有线索了  给艾弗里看看
Lead just came in now. Let's get it to Avery.
有什么线索
What have you got?
绷带的化验结果出来了
Lab results came back on that bandage,
检测出了甲醛  甲醇和乙醇
tested positive for formaldehyde, methanol and ethanol.
-防腐液  -防腐液
- Embalming fluid.  - Embalming fluid.
鉴证组在中央车站发现了微量甲醛
The lab found traces of formaldehyde at Grand Central
在旋转木马发现了乙醇
and ethanol at the Carousel.
凶手在太平间工作
Our killer works at a mortuary.
也许是医护人员
Or he could be a hospital employee.
或是太平间的门房
Or a janitor at a morgue.
不对  卡塞尔的推论更有可能
No. Castle's theory is more likely.
调查全市所有太平间
Bring up all the mortuaries in the city.
单是纽约市区就有上千个太平间
We've got over a thousand in the New York city area alone.
不可能在午夜前全部排查
We can't hit all these before midnight.
你能不能同时搜索一个人的
Can you cross-reference mortuary experience
犯罪记录和在太平间的工作经历
with criminal records?
或有前科的求职者
Or job finder groups for ex-cons.
-对  -我试试
-Yes!  - I can try.
六个人
Six names.
各小组行动  午夜前
Mobilize the troops. I want every one of these guys
将他们全部收押
in our custody before midnight.
我明白了为什么你会说他有用
I see what you mean about him being helpful.
有没有可疑的殡仪人员
Any of these undertakers look good for it?
他们的回答如出一辙
They all say the same thing,
"我们整天跟死人打交道
"We work with dead bodies all day,
不需要再制造死尸"
we don't need to make more."
这是他的诱饵  和那个指纹一样
He baited us, just like with that fingerprint.
我们在浪费时间
We're wasting our time.
他打来电话  找妮基·希特
He's on the phone. He's asking for Nikki Heat.
我们在追踪电话
We're tracing the call.
喂
Hello.
妮基
Nikki?
你应该阻止我的
You were supposed to stop me.
我想让你阻止我
I wanted you to stop me.
告诉我你在哪里
Tell me where you are.
你会一个人过来吗
Will you come alone?
是的  就你跟我
Yes, just you and me.
我们可以解决问题
We can figure this out.
我可以帮你  你只需相信我
I can help you. You just need to trust me.
告诉我
Tell me something...
失败的滋味如何
how does it feel to know that you have failed?
检查楼道  派一队人上楼顶
Check the stairs. Get a unit on the roof.
监控整栋大楼
I want eyes on every inch of this structure.
他刚刚还在这里  尸体不会太远
He was just here. That body can't be too far.
看这里有一滩血
Over here! A lot of blood.
一只女人的鞋
A woman's shoe.
鞋跟断了
Got a broken heel.
还有几缕头发
Strands of hair.
看起来她挣扎过
Looks like she put up a fight.
这里有四个弹壳
There's four shell casings.
没有抢救措施  她不可能还活着
There's no way she would've survived without medical attention.
那尸体在哪里
Then where's the body?
他总把尸体留在犯案现场
He always leaves the body where he kills.
并且总在人流密集的惹眼地点作案
And he always kills in famous places with lots of foot traffic.
他在改变作案方式
He's changing his M.O.
这下更难预测他的行动
Which makes him more unpredictable,
他也变得更危险了
which makes him more dangerous.
整栋楼都搜遍了  没有尸体
Structure's clear. There's no body.
他到底把她放哪儿了
Where the hell did he put her?
他把她放进车尾箱了
He put her in his trunk.
血迹到这里就没有了
That blood trail ends right here.
他守株待兔  也许车都没熄火
So he waited, probably left his car idling,
行凶后  打开车尾箱把她放进去
takes down his victim, popped his trunk, put her in,
开车离开  尸体就在车上
drove away, body on board.
叫停车场保安
Get the parking attendant
提供所有车辆资料
to give us a list of all the vehicles through here
还有监控录像
and the video footage.
你觉得他会用自己的车吗
You think he used his own car?
不会  但如果是今晚偷来的车
No, but if he stole it tonight,
他也许来不及换车牌
he might not have had time to switch the plates.
发布全面通缉令
We put out an A.P.B.
我让手下去拿每月
I'll get my guys to get a roster of all the people who had
在这层停车的车主名单
monthlies on this floor.
我的手下已经去拿了
My people are already on it.
我手下的人比你多
I got way more people than you do.
你上司已经派人保护了你的公寓
Your captain has a unit on your apartment.
-回家休息  -不需要
- Go home. Get some rest.  - It's not necess--
别争了  你要是累垮了对我也没好处
No argument. You're no good to me if you're burned out.
他像困兽一样在发狂地咆哮
He roars like an angry, caged animal.
注意力全放在舱门外
Concentrate towards the outer hatch area.
他的手好像没有因为爆炸而受伤
The blows don't seem to be injuring his hands.
我没看见血
There's no--there's no blood that I can see.
为什么还不睡
What are you still doing up?
睡不着  脑子很乱
Oh, can't sleep. Too much on my mind.
做决定不容易啊
You know, decisions to make and...
你的婚礼录影带之一
Wow. One of your old wedding videos.
少来了
Oh-ho-ho. Are you kidding?
和我前夫们相比  这家伙简直小菜一碟
This guy's a pushover compared to my ex-husbands.
这么说优势大过于劣势了吗
So the pros outweighed the cons?
亲爱的  暂停你这儿并非长久之计
Darling, this was always supposed to be a temporary situation
我最终要过回我自己的生活
un-until I got back on my feet, you know.
姓罗杰斯的女人总是随心所欲
Well, the Rodgers women always follow their hearts.
没错
Yeah.
你没事吧
You okay?
这个案子...
This case, it just...
如果不是因为我的书
If it wasn't for my book--
你打算怎么做  亲爱的
What are you gonna do, darling,
因为某些白痴神经短路  就不写了吗
Stop writing because some idiot has got a screw loose?
不是  只是
No, it's just...
我从未想过要让她置身险境
I never intended to put her in harm's way.
就我所知的凯特·贝克特
Let me tell you something about Kate Beckett.
她会照顾好自己
That gal can take care of herself.
真的
Really.
卡塞尔  你来这里干嘛
Castle? What are you doing here?
喝红酒吗
Wine?
你的保镖们去哪儿了
So what happened to your security detail?
我没看到外面有人
I didn't see anyone outside.
我回来后  就让他们回家了
I sent them home after I got in.
怎么了
What?
窗户和门都锁好了
The windows are locked, the door is locked,
我有枪
I'm armed.
之前凶手都弃尸在作案现场
So our guy killed the others where they were found.
为何这个女孩例外呢
Why not this girl?
为何凶手不把她留在停车场
Why didn't he just leave her in the garage where we'd find her?
他改变作案方式了
He's changing it up.
可能这个死者很特别
Or this victim is special.
我不喝  谢谢
Oh, no, thanks.
喝吧  特工肖说我们需要减压
No, no, Agent Shaw said we need to decompress.
2000年产自教皇新城堡  减压佳酿
Nothing decompresses like a 2000 chateauneuf-du-Pape.
好吧  如果特工肖真这么说过
Oh, well, if special Agent Shaw said so...
-这是什么意思  -没什么
- What is that supposed to mean?  - Nothing.
你听她说话时的样子还有
I just see the way that you listen to her,
看那些高档设备时的样子  我都看在眼里
the way that you look at all of her fancy equipment.
现在我的普通白板已经不上档次了
Now my murder board's not enough for you?
-她那个智能板你才看得上眼  -你吃醋了
- Now you need a smart board? - Are you jealous?
我不是吃醋  只是尴尬
I'm not jealous. I'm just embarrassed...
你的表现就像个十岁小孩
The way that you act like a 10 year old,
那么崇拜她的二维条码
all impressed by her data matrix.
"处理信息太迅速了  特工肖
"Oh, it collates information so quickly, Agent Shaw.
给我讲讲吧"
Tell me all about it."
你还真够离谱的
You are ridiculous.
最糟糕的是  你居然和她一起推理
And then to top it off, you are now building theory with her.
怎么了
So?
你本应该和我一起推理
So you're supposed to be building theory with me.
你本应是我团队里的一员
You're supposed to be on my team.
我们和特工肖也是同一团队啊
Well, I thought we were all on the same team.
没错  只是如果你灵光一闪
We are. It's just... I think that if you have an insight,
应该第一个告诉我
you should run it by me first.
我会的  喝你的红酒吧
Fine. I will. Now drink your wine.
谢谢
Thanks.
但我累了
But I am tired.
我要睡觉了
And... I need to go to bed.
不  我不会走的
Oh, no. I'm not leaving.
我是来保护你的
I'm here to protect you.
什么  就凭你的唇枪舌剑吗
What, with your vast arsenal of rapier wit?
因为我  外面有个疯子要杀你
There is a madman gunning for you because of me.
我不会留下你一个人的
I am not going to leave you alone.
好吧  我太累了不想吵架
Okay, fine. I am too tired to argue.
但如果让我看见门把手动了
But if I see that doorknob turn,
卡塞尔先生  注意了
I will have you know Mr. Castle,
-我睡觉时也握着枪  -明白
- that I sleep with a gun.  - Understood.
你还在这儿  你在做薄饼吗
You're still here... and you're making pancakes?
我本来想做熏肉鸡蛋  但鸡蛋过期了
I was hoping for bacon and eggs, but your eggs are expired
还有你家的熏肉长毛了
and your bacon has something furry on it.
我几乎都是叫外卖
Yeah, well, I mostly order in.
我从冰箱里堆积如山的
I figured that from the styrofoam temple
塑料外卖盒看出来了
you've got going on in that refrigerator.
咖啡煮好了  不过我觉得过滤器坏了
Coffee's brewed. I think your filter's broken though.
我稍后为你订个新的
I'll order you a new one later.
你可真周到啊
Wow. Looks like you thought of everything.
除了报纸
Except the paper.
卡塞尔  我们没时间看报纸
Castle, we don't have time for the paper.
有具尸体等着我们去找呢
There's a body out there that I gotta find.
看来她找到你了
Looks like it found you.
你们刚刚起床  对吗
So you had just gotten up, right?
是的  卡塞尔刚做好早餐
Yeah. Castle just finished making breakfast,
接着他走到门前
and he went to the door--
怎样的早餐
What kind of breakfast?
什么
Uh, I'm sorry?
他做的什么早餐
What kind of breakfast was he making?
薄饼
Pancakes.
真有居家的感觉啊
Well, isn't that domestic?
回到正题
Anyway,
报纸通常4点到  我们7点起的
the paper usually arrives at 4:00, and we were up at 7:00.
就是说凶手有三小时的时间
So that means the killer had a 3-hour window
可以把尸体放在那里而不被人发现
where he could've left the body there unnoticed.
那你和卡塞尔先生
And exactly what time
昨晚上床睡觉时间是几点
did you and Mr. Castle go to bed last night?
口供已经录完了
I think we're done here.
老兄  我看见贝克特穿着睡衣
Dude, I see Beckett in her jammies...
桌上还有红酒杯
wine glasses on the table.
贝克特和我什么也没发生
There's nothing going on with Beckett and me.
我们的关系和以前一样
No more than there was yesterday.
老兄  你给她做薄饼
Dude, you made her pancakes?
早餐而已
It's just breakfast.
薄饼可不只是早餐而已
Pancakes is not just breakfast.
这是用食物来表达
It's an edible way of saying,
"非常感谢美妙的一夜"
"Thank you so much for last night."
卡塞尔  我们是哥们儿
Castle, come on. We're your friends.
透露点细节
Details.
好吧  靠近点
All right. Come here.
没有细节
There are no details.
我现在都无法正视你
I can't even look at you right now.
目击证人拒绝合作
Witness refuses to cooperate.
现在知道他带走尸体的原因了
Now we know why he took the body.
"我知道你住在哪儿"  这是恐吓
"I know where you live." This was a threat.
不只是恐吓
More than that.
他是说他对你很失望
He's saying he's disappointed in you.
他的想法是
In his mind,
他已经事先警告你他会再次行凶
he gave you fair warning that he was going to kill again.
要是你再聪明一点  你本可以阻止他
If you had been smarter, you would've been able to stop him.
他在暗示  "她因你而亡"
He's saying, "This one is on you."
我只是在分析他  探长
I'm profiling him, Detective,
不是附和他
not agreeing with him.
这家伙是个疯子
The guy is a friggin' nut bar.
不要受他的影响
Don't let him get to you.
这个标题够讽刺的吧
Talk about irony.
-知道死者的身份吗  -现在还不知道
- Do we have an I.D. on our vic? - No, not yet.
没有手提包  也没接到失踪人口的报案
There's no purse, no missing person's report filed.
验尸官的车在楼下
The coroner's van's downstairs.
我们要把尸体运到停尸房
We need to get the body to the morgue
把子弹取出来
and pull the slugs.
四处枪伤
Only four entry wounds.
如果犯罪手法没有变化
If the pattern holds,
他会给我们留下一个四个字母的单词
he should have a 4-letter word for us.
真有意思
That's funny.
我也有一个四个字母的单词给他
I have a 4-letter word for him, too.
你们两个护送运尸车吧
Why don't you two escort the body to the morgue
有什么发现通知我
and let me know what you find?
当然  先把衣服穿好
Once you're dressed, of course.
听说尸体被发现的时候
Hey. Heard you two were making pancakes
你俩正在煎薄饼
when the body dropped.
-什么都没发生  -是啊
- Nothing happened. - Right.
你有什么发现吗
So what do you got?
弹壳上有字母
Letters on the slugs.
"B-u-r-"
"B-u-r--"
"燃烧"  妮基将身陷火海
"Burn." Nikki will burn.
真吓人
Well, that's chilling.
系统中没有死者的指纹
Our victim's fingerprints aren't in the system.
你有什么能鉴别她身份的发现吗
Do you have anything that can I.D. her?
我在她身上发现了甲醛
Well, I found formaldehyde on her.
那是凶手身上的
Yeah, that's from the killer.
他在其他犯罪现场也留下了
He left it at the other scenes as well.
不是微量的
Not traces.
是在她指甲缝和头发里发现的
It was under her fingernails, in her hair.
她的工作需要接触防腐液
She worked with embalming fluid.
我还发现了微量的泥土
I also found traces of clay,
聚安酯和动物血液
polyurethane and animal blood.
我不知道她是谁  但我知道她的职业
I don't know who she is, but I can tell you what she does.
她是动物标本剥制师
She's a taxidermist.
你俩异口同声的样子真是太可爱了
It's so cute, the way you two do that.
剥制术
Taxidermy?
防腐液和动物毛发是
Embalming fluid plus animal hair
诺曼·贝茨最爱的消遣活动[《惊魂记》男主角]
equals Norman Bates' favorite pastime.
在前两个凶案现场我们也发现了防腐液
It can't be just a coincidence that we found embalming fluid
这不可能仅仅是个巧合
at our first two crime scenes as well.
所以凶手和第三位死者有关联
So the killer and this victim were connected.
似乎如此
It seems so.
市区只有七家动物标本商店
So there's only seven taxidermy shops in the city.
我的手下正在逐个排查
My guys are running them down right now.
但是如果他们之间有交集
But if there was a connection between them,
对比处理系统怎么没有发现
why didn't comparison matrix find it?
可能不是同事或者去同一家健身房
Maybe it's not as simple as a work relationship
那么简单的联系
or going to the same gym.
就像你说的  得用心去理解罪犯的心理
Like you said, it takes a mind to hunt a mind.
第三名死者的身份确认了
We got an I.D. on our third vic.
她叫桑德拉·凯勒
Her name is Sandra Keller.
在市中心的一家标本商店工作
She works at a taxidermy shop downtown.
她和凶手有什么关系吗
Any connection between her and our killer?
她的同事声称死者曾与一男性顾客争执
A colleague of hers said she had a run-in with a guy
该男子长相可能与画像相符
who maybe matched our sketch--
他的比熊犬
a customer whose bichon frise
被公园里的一只罗特威尔牧犬咬死
had been killed in the park by another dog--a rottweiler.
这位顾客悲痛欲绝  他预付一半费用
Customer was heartbroken. He paid half up front to have his
想把"南瓜先生"做成标本永久保存
Mr. Bumpkins preserved for eternity.
但当他回来取标本的时候
When he came back to pick up his dog,
却拿不出剩余的费用
didn't have the fee.
桑德拉拒绝交出"南瓜先生"的标本
When Sandra refused to give up stuffed Bumpkins,
该男子大怒  然后冲出商店
the guy went ballistic and stormed out of the store.
事发两天后的晚上  商店被盗
Two nights later, they had a break-in.
失窃的物品包括该男子的
Among the things that went missing are this guy's
比熊犬标本和几罐防腐液
stuffed bichon frise and a bunch of embalming fluid.
这就解释了我们在现场发现的微量防腐液
That explains why we found traces of it at the murder scenes.
该男子还破坏了商店的电脑
He also trashed the store's computer.
所有客户的名字和资料都没了
There's no client data, no name.
我的探员们询问了所有
My agents interviewed all of
委托米歇尔·刘易斯溜狗的客户
Michelle Lewis' dog walking clients.
一对情侣被迫人道毁灭他们的罗特威尔牧犬
One couple had to put their rottweiler down because
因为米歇尔没能控制住它
Michelle lost control of it,
导致其咬死了一只狗
and it killed another dog.
死的是"南瓜先生"  所以在悲伤的打击之下
Mr. Bumpkins. So grief-stricken,
凶手将爱犬之死
our killer blames Michelle and Sandra
归咎于米歇尔和桑德拉  他决定报复
for the loss of his best friend and decides to get revenge.
为一只狗杀了三个人
All of this about a dog?
这和妮基·希特有什么关系
What does this have to do with Nikki Heat?
狗是导火索
The dog's the trigger.
也许小狗死的时候凶手正在看这本书
Maybe he was reading the book when it was killed.
当他崩溃的时候
When he snapped,
不知怎么他就把这事归咎于妮基了
he somehow blamed Nikki for it.
听起来有点荒唐
It seems a little absurd.
你肯定是个爱猫之人  探长
You must be a cat lover, Detective.
他在为杀人找理由  这就是理由
He's looking for a reason to kill. This is it.
那第一名死者呢
What about our first vic?
彼得曼是怎么被卷进去的
How does Peterman fit in to all this?
他是一名人身伤害诉讼律师
Well, he was a personal injury lawyer.
可能凶手想提出一起
Maybe our murderer wanted to file
人为过失致狗死亡的诉讼
a wrongful doggy death suit.
根据彼得曼的记录
According to Peterman's notes,
一月  他曾与本·康纳德见面
Back in January, he had a meeting with a Ben Conrad
讨论一起狗死亡的诉讼
over a lawsuit about a dead dog.
但彼得曼拒绝接手此案
Peterman declined to take the case though.
这就是拼图的最后一块
That's the last piece of our puzzle.
关于康纳德有什么资料
What do you have on Conrad?
只有一张车管局的照片
Just a photo from the D.M.V.
找到你了  你这疯杂种
Got you, you son of a bitch.
是的
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
好  亲爱的
Okay, sweetie.
妈妈要去抓坏人了  好吗
Mommy's gotta go arrest somebody, okay?
我会回家吃晚饭的  好的  我爱你
I'll be home for dinner. All right. I love you.
拜拜
Bye.
-你是位母亲  -是啊
- You're a mom? - Yeah.
你可以把枪收起来了
And you can holster your gun.
你们两个留在这里
You're both staying here.
什么  别这样
What? No, come no.
这是最后的缉捕  你不能让她这么做
This is the final takedown. You can't let her do this to us.
特工肖说的对  我是他的目标
No, Agent Shaw is right. I'm his target.
我要是步入交火区
I can't compromise your team
会成为包袱
by walking into the line of fire.
我们会把他拿下的  犯人还是你的
We'll take him down. It'll still be your collar.
她居然是位母亲  我真是没想到
Wow. She's a mom. I never would've pegged her for that.
我本以为她是个没时间顾家的工作狂
I figured she was a career-driven woman with no time for a family.
不是人人都会为了工作不要家庭
Well, not everybody makes that choice.
他打电话找你
He's calling for you.
接过来
Put him on.
喂
Hello.
你自以为聪明过人是吧  妮基
Oh, you think you're so smart, don't you, Nikki?
你以为你找到我  你就赢了吗
You think, what, just because you found me that you won?
他知道我们到了
He knows we're here.
结束了  本  投降吧
It's over, Ben. Time to give up.
不  没有结束
No, it's not over!
本  听我说  你被包围了
Ben, listen to me. You're surrounded.
放下武器
I need you to put the gun down.
妮基  你知道我不会束手就擒的
You know I can't do that, Nikki.
本  举手投降
Ben, I need you to step outside of your apartment
走出房间
with your hands raised.
游戏不是这样玩的  你我中必死一人
That's not our game. One of us has to die.
没人必须要死
No one has to die.
总有人必须要死
Somebody always has to die!
既然死的不是你
And since it can't be you...
本
Ben.
冲
Go!
快  快  快
Go! Go! Go!
厨房没人
Kitchen's clear!
浴室没人
Bathroom's clear!
我们会做弹道检测
We're sending the gun to ballistics,
这枪是点45口径的  很可能就是
but given it's a .45, it's probably the same one
他作案的凶器
he used on our other victims.
很可能就是准备用来杀你的凶器
And probably the same one he was gonna use on you.
其实  不是的
Uh, actually, no.
他有个更轰轰烈烈的计划
He was planning something a little bit more spectacular.
电话
Cell phones?
他在做引爆装置
He was making a detonator.
永别了  妮基  永别了  妮基
Good-bye, Nikki. Good-bye, Nikki.
他从偷来的防腐液中
He was extracting formaldehyde
提取甲醛就是要制造旋风炸药
from the embalming fluid he stole to create cyclonite--
一种近似军用的烈性炸药
a near military-grade explosive.
你分析他时  说他很可能是个纵火犯
When you profiled him, you said he was probably an arsonist.
我也说了他喜欢搞出大场面
I also said he liked to make a big scene.
警局内部构造分析图
Schematics of the precinct.
他想干掉你
He was planning on killing you
整个警局也一起埋葬
and taking the whole station with you.
"妮基将葬身火海"  还挺有诗意的
"Nikki will burn." I can see the poetry in that.
十恶不赦  嗜杀成魔的罪恶诗篇
The terrible, homicidal poetry.
我只是没料到他会自杀
I just wouldn't have profiled this guy as suicidal.
可能一旦我们发现了他
I guess once we found him,
自杀就成了他能掌控局势的唯一方式
it was the only way he could control the situation.
至少康纳德自杀让我们免去了种种麻烦
Well, at least Conrad saved us the trouble of a trial.
值得庆贺的是  我不在你眼前晃来晃去了
And the best news is, I'm out of your hair.
值得庆贺的是
The best news...
这案子结了
is that it's over.
我以为你一小时前就睡了
I thought you went to bed an hour ago.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
这案子不是结了吗
I thought the case was over.
是的  干净漂亮地结了
Oh, it is. Wrapped up all nice and neat.
这是好事  是吧
That's a good thing, right?
在书里  是好事
In a book, that's a good thing.
但现实生活中  没有什么能这么利落地解决
In real life, nothing is that neat.
谁让你辗转反侧了
What's got you still up?
奶奶
Gram.
我真不敢相信她明天就要走了
I can't believe she's leaving tomorrow.
的确  她刚搬进来时
I mean, yeah, when she first moved in,
我无法想象她时刻都在我身边的景象
I couldn't imagine having her around all the time.
但现在我...  无法想象她离开后会怎样
But now I... can't imagine her being gone.
听着
Listen...
这就是生活
It's a fact of life.
我们所爱的人总会离开我们
People we love leave us.
除非你把他们铐在暖气片上
Unless you chain 'em to a radiator,
而出于某种原因  这属于非法行为
which for some reason is illegal.
但是  凭我对她的了解
But, uh... knowing her...
她半年内一定会搬回来的
she'll be back in six months.
太好了  你们都没睡
Oh, good. You're both up.
亲爱的  你得来帮我决定下该搬些什么
Darling, I need you to help me decide on what to take.
我得把箱子搬下来
Oh, and I need to get my bags down.
理查德  能搭把手吗
Richard, could you give us a hand?
手
A hand.
怎么了
What?
第二个受害者身上的淤痕
The bruising pattern on the second victim--
显示凶手用的是左手
the killer used his left hand.
还有  看看他的字迹
And... you see his handwriting?
看"4"的倾斜度和"6"圈的写法
Look at the slope on the "4" And the loop on the "6."
没错  这么说他是左撇子
Yeah. So he was left-handed.
本·康纳德用右手开枪自杀
Well, Ben Conrad shot himself with his right hand.
如果当时窗口那人是本·康纳德
If the man in the window was Ben Conrad ,
他就会用左手开枪自杀
he would've shot himself on the left side.
本·康纳德没有自杀
Ben Conrad didn't kill himself.
本·康纳德被当时站在窗口的人杀了
Ben Conrad was murdered by the man in the window.
本  本不是凶手
Ben--Ben's not our killer.
-真正的凶手只是在耍我们  -但有证据...
- The real killer was just playing with us. - But the evidence--
这只是凶手设的套  让我们以为本是凶手
No, it was--it was planted there to lead us to Ben.
他想让我们以为案子结了
He wants us to think it's over.
他想让我们放松警惕
He wants us to drop our guard.
他要制造大场面
He wants to make a big scene.
"妮基将葬身火海"
"Nikki will burn."
天哪
Oh, God.
蒙哥马利撤掉了保护  她现在是孤身一人
Montgomery took the detail off her place. She's alone.
她没接  打给警局
She's not picking up. Call the precinct.
叫增援立刻到她家
Tell them to get over there right away.
通知警局我们错了  凶手还没死
Tell them we were wrong. Tell them the killer's still alive.
我一走你就把门锁上  不要让任何人进来
You lock this door behind me. Don't let anyone in.
请接蒙哥马利长官  是的  告诉他事情紧急
Captain montgomery, please. Yes, tell him it's an emergency.
求你了  贝克特  快接电话
Come on, Beckett. Pick up. Pick up the phone. Pick it up!
怎么了  卡塞尔
What, Castle?
不是他  本·康纳德不是凶手
It wasn't Ben Conrad. He's not the killer!
凶手还没死  凶手还活着
The killer's still alive! The killer's still alive!
永别了  妮基
Good-bye, Nikki.
凯特
Kate!